and the number one thing that causes
guys to not achieve the expectations
they have of trt is regular alcohol
consumption and there's a huge cohort of
men who don't understand because of you
know culture practices or you know their
own biases or you know for whatever
reason that you can't drink you know two
to three beers a night or 10 to 12 Beers
on the weekend and be healthy now there
can be an exception to the rule you
might say well I know this guy who you
know drinks like that and he doesn't
have cool exceptions don't disprove
rules that's not how science works but
for the vast majority of guys alcohol
consumption is the number one thing
holding back their trt that is so easy
to fix I mean losing 10 20 30 kilos of
body fat that's difficult not picking up
a beer bottle and going like this is
much easier um so it's an easy thing to
stop and it's an easy thing to cut out
and the the there was a study that came
out recently Ronda Patrick referenced it
where it showed that basically lifetime
consumption of standard drinks equated
in terms of uh negative outcomes on
mortality as cigarettes so one one beer
is as bad as one cigarette for your
overall health so alcohol is terrible
and I think that everyone is so much
better off not drinking any alcohol I
think the best approach if people do
want to drink alcohol is to have one to
two drinks on a special occasion Friday
night is not a special occasion and if
people are going to be you know for the
guys who are like red wine connoisseurs
or whiskey connoisseurs or craft beer
connoisseurs I think the absolute
maximum you can look at drinking is one
to two drinks one to two times per week
but you'd be significantly better off
with zero or at the lower end of that
and for guys who are going to insist on
continuing to drink I think you should
take glutathione But to answer this
guy's question he is going to be much
better off without it his entire body is
going to function much better without it
it's not going to impact his
testosterone numbers well I mean if he
was drinking two or three beers a night
it could be impacting his liver's
ability to metabolize the Esther so it
could impact his numbers depending on
what his individual alcohol tolerance
was but for the most part it will reduce
his Ser active protein it will reduce
his LDL it will reduce his triglycerides
it will generally reduce a and ALT it
will reduce blood pressure it will
reduce hematocrit hemoglobin um and it
will increase his overall Sleep Quality
his well-being uh his igf-1 levels will
all increase so blood moves in very
favorable directions when people stop
drinking like this and two to three
drinks a night it's a lot of alcohol
like over the course of a week that's a
lot of
alcohol yeah well it's easy Dave to say
when you don't drink at all but I have
also a lot of patients in my practice uh
who think it's very normal to have one
drink a day two drinks a day lot of
people think that's just normal social
socially
accepted yes yes and that this this
casual alcoholism is one of the most
challenging things for guys to unlearn
when they get on trt because I see guys
all the time who were spending hundreds
of dollars a month on gut supplements I
mean if if you're having gut issues and
you're drinking alcohol don't worry
about the gut supplements to stop
drinking booze and it will get way
better um but I see guys who are
biohacking and eating super clean and
and working really hard on their diets
and then they're binge drinking on a
Friday night or they're drinking a
couple of drinks every night and they
don't realize that they're completely
derailing all the hard work they're
doing and it's just not worth it the the
the the buzz and the um the intoxication
that people get from alcohol not only is
it very mild relative to the damage
they're doing but it makes you feel like
the next day and if people are
drinking like this and you stop drinking
for a couple of weeks take a photo
before and after and you're face will
look noticeably less bloed